Register of the Harry Qualman collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Harry Qualman collection
1950-1980
2005C69
Hoover Institution Archives
9 manuscript boxes (3.6 linear feet)
Reports, studies, government documents, serial issues, and other printed matter relating to cooperation among French-speaking countries, administration of Madagascar and of New Caledonia, technical assistance to these countries, and the work of the South Pacific Commission.
Qualman, Harry, collector.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2005.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Reports, studies, government documents, serial issues, and other printed matter relating to cooperation among French-speaking countries, administration of Madagascar and of New Caledonia, technical assistance to these countries, and the work of the South Pacific Commission.
French-speaking countries.; Madagascar.; New Caledonia.; South Pacific Commission.; International cooperation.; Technical assistance.
- Agence de Coopération Culturelle et Technique File, 1969-1975
  Scope and Contents note
  Records of the organization of French-speaking countries pertaining to news, policy, and justice.
  - Budget propositions, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - Conseil d'Administration, 1970 June (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Legal documents, 1970 (Box-folder 3: 8)
  - General conference, 1971 October 11-15 (Box 2)
  - Quebec conference, 1971 (Box-folder 4: 6)
  - Reports, 1969 February - 1975 November (Box-folder 1: 3)
- Madagascar File, 1950-1976
  Includes records pertaining to news, French cooperative economic and industrial development projects, and international and domestic policy implementation.
  - General, 1964-1969 (Box-folder 1: 1, 4: 1)
  - Budget, 1961-1968 (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - Development, 1961, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 6: 2, 7: 2)
  - Economic problems, 1960-1966 (Box-folder 9: 3)
  - Economic and statistic research, tomes I-II, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 9: 1-2)
  - Economy and statistics, 1950-1968, 1972 (Box-folder 6: 1, 8: 3-5)
  - Economy and industry, 1960-1965, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 7: 4-5)
  - French cooperation, 1962, 1973 (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - International relations reports, 1960s (Box 4)
  - News, 1965-1966, 1976 (Box-folder 5: 3)
  - Policy, 1964-1970, 1976 (Box-folder 8: 1-2)
  - Regional geography, 1967 (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - Second Legislature, 1956-1960 (Box-folder 4: 1)
- South Pacific Commission (SPC) File, 1950-1966
  Materials related to the regional intergovernmental organization (whose membership includes both nations and territories in the Pacific Ocean and their metropolitan powers), especially in the areas of general economic advancement and policy implementation.
  - General, 1950-1964 (Box-folder 3: 1-2)
  - Economic development reports, 1964 (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - Economic and budget reports, 1964-1966 (Box-folder 9: 7)
  - W. D. Forsyth correspondence, 1964 April-October (Box-folder 9: 6)
    Relates to future organizational and economic plans of the South Pacific Commission.
  - Policy reports, 1955-1966 (Box-folder 9: 5)
  - Proceedings, 1952-1965 (Box-folder 6: 3-5)
- Printed Matter, 1950-1980
  - Agecop liaison, 1980 July - August (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - "Canada and Francophone Africa,", 1970-1976 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - Constitution of Mali, 1974 July (Box-folder 5: 2)
  - "Cultural Action and the South Pacific,", 1950, 1962-1972 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - "Cultural and Technical Report,", 1969 October 1 (Box-folder 4: 4)
  - Deux-Tiers Francophone, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 1: 2)
    Information magazine on news in French-speaking countries.
  - Etudes Internationales, 1974 June (Box-folder 6: 8)
  - Francophone Bibliographie 1960-1969 and Communautés Francophones Bibliographie Chroniques 1970-1972, 1972, 1973 (Box-folder 3: 5)
    News and International Relations of Quebec.
  - Francophone dictionary, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 3: 6, 4: 7)
    On the evolution of partially or fully French-speaking countries.
  - "Francophone Political News,", undated (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - "Francophone Reports,", 1968 June - 1970 March (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - "Francophone Reflections,", 1965-1971 (Box 1)
  - International Association of Parliament-French Language, 1970 March-May (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - Jeune Afrique, 1974 September (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - L'Organisation Commune Africaine et Malgache, Niamey conference program, 1969 February (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - Official Journal of the French Republic, 1960 June-July (Box-folder 4: 2)
  - "Programa de Salud Integral San Antonio,", 1976-1977 (Box-folder 6: 7)
  - "Projet d'Implantation de l'Ecole Internationale de Bordeaux,", 1972 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - "Reorganization of the California State Personnel Board" report, 1961 (Box-folder 6: 7)
  - Bulletin de Liaison Pédagogique de l'Enseignement Technique et Professionnel, 1971 January (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - South Pacific health benefits and publications, 1963, 1965 (Box-folder 9: 4)
  - South Pacific magazines, 1964 October - 1965 June (Box-folder 4: 3)